<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-06-21T20:44:31+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">21st-century man</title><subtitle>A place for exploration</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why 21st century man?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/06/21/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why 21st century man?" /><published>2022-06-21T19:09:51+02:00</published><updated>2022-06-21T19:09:51+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/06/21/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/06/21/welcome-to-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<p>I am quite inspired by the late Christopher Hitchens. He defined his life in many ways with his writings on politics, contrarianism, and religion. His book <em>Letters to a young contrarian</em> has been a much bigger part of my life than I would dare to admit. The essence of the book can be summed up as follows:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You should try to live your life as if you were a free person, not having to wonder what everyone’s opinion was. That you should take the risk of being the only person believing what you believe in and that still might mean that you were right; that if the majority believes a certain way, it makes it more likely than not to be wrong.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>There is a lot of common and established knowledge that I find myself rejecting in day-to-day life. Ideas that would be controversial to some while still rally others. I still find it shocking to feel the need to mention that I am a classical liberal to avoid controversy, however, this is what we as a people have grown accustomed to.<br /></p>

<hr />

<p><br />I see there is a great need for people today to speak up. Society has grown scared and is badly in need of healing. And we do not realize how important it is for everyone to make their voice heard. So let me ask you this:</p>

<p><strong><em>How tolerant is a society when ideologies break families apart?</em></strong></p>

<p><strong><em>How good is criticism when hidden behind a black screen?</em></strong></p>

<p><strong><em>How good is a democracy with a silent majority?</em></strong></p>

<p>Politics is a big topic today. However, I do not want this to be a discussion of current affairs. I want to explore our systems be they political, societal, or technological. This is a place for exploration of ideas, contrarianism, and questioning.</p>

<p>I invite you to question these ideas, to criticize me for my shortcomings, and my biases. How good is an explorer with a map only partially filled in? and that refuses to explore?</p>

<p>In a way, it is a call to arms, but we will leave that for another time<br /></p>

<hr />

<p><br />So let’s ask the question again.</p>

<p><strong><em>Why did I create 21st-century man?</em></strong></p>

<p>I find myself wanting to write more, explore my ideas more, to formulate them better.</p>

<p>This is my place for exploration.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am quite inspired by the late Christopher Hitchens. He defined his life in many ways with his writings on politics, contrarianism, and religion. His book Letters to a young contrarian has been a much bigger part of my life than I would dare to admit. The essence of the book can be summed up as follows:]]></summary></entry></feed>